# 哈喽大家好 我是王刚
Hi everyone, this is Wang Gang
# 本期视频我给大家分享一道家常菜
In this video I will share an everyday dish
# 土豆拌茄子
Eggplant and Potato Cold Dish
# 处理食材之前首先我们准备1盆清水
Before we preprocess the ingredients, prepare a basin of water
# 然后在清水中加入适量的白醋
Then add some rice vinegar to the water
# 准备好之后放一边备用
Then set it aside
# 准备土豆1个去皮之后切成小颗粒备用
Prepare a potato, remove the skin, and dice it
# 嫌麻烦的同学也可以切成4毫米左右的片
If that's too much for you, you can cut it into 4mm-thick slices
# 这一步的目的是让土豆更容易成熟
This is to make the potato easier to be cooked
# 切好之后放入白醋水中浸泡备用
Having cut the potatos, put it in the water with rice vinegar
# 准备茄子1条对半切开之后切成小块备用
Prepare an eggplant, slice it in half, and cut it to small pieces
# 同学们茄子大约切成土豆的3倍大小即可
These pieces should be 3 times as large as the potato ones
# 然后放入盆中浸泡备用
Then put them in the basin too
# 加醋浸泡土豆和茄子可以防止其氧化变黑
Adding vinegar and placing the potato and eggplant in the mixture can prevent them from oxidizing and turning dark
# 但是同学们切记土豆不能泡太久（60分钟以上）
But keep in mind, we can't leave them there for too long (more than 60 minutes)
# 否则土豆将会变软口感不好
Or the potato will soften and can't have the same texture
# 然后我们将土豆茄子和醋水直接上锅蒸25分钟左右
Then we steam the potato and eggplant in the mixture for 25 minutes
# 这样能够最大限度的保证茄子的紫色
This will keep the purple color of the eggplant from fading as much as possible
# 下一步开始准备料汁
Next, prepare the sauce
# 准备大蒜几颗拍散之后剁碎备用
Prepare a few garlic cloves, break them up, and mince them
# 准备小葱头几根切碎备用
Prepare a few green onions and mince them
# 碗中加入蚝油4克
Add 4g of oyster sauce to the bowl
# 加入生抽酱油12克
Add 12g of light soy sauce
# 加入少许白糖（约1克）
Add a little bit of sugar (around 1g)
# 搅拌均匀之后加入适量的香辣红油拌匀即可
Mix them, add some red chili oil, and mix again
# 不能吃辣的同学也可以不加
If you don't like spicy food, you can skip this step
# 25分钟之后将蒸熟软的茄子和土豆捞出沥干水分
After 25 minutes, take the softened eggplant and potato out and remove the moisture
# 待稍微凉一会之后倒入盘中
Let them rest till they turn cold and place them in a plate
# 最后将调好的料汁淋在上面即可
Finally pour the sauce over the veggies
# 一道非常开胃下饭的土豆拌茄子就制作完成
A really appetizing dish that's great with rice, Eggplant and Potato Cold Dish, is ready to be served
# 下面开始技术总结
# 第一，土豆不能切太大否则不能熟透，茄子应切大块些这样才能久蒸
# 第二，原料泡在水里面蒸可以有效防止营养流失
# 第三，此菜必须将水份沥干再淋料汁，否则口味容易冲淡
# 土豆拌茄子的技术总结完毕
Now let's summarize the techniques
First, the potato can't be diced into large pieces or they won't be fully cooked, while the eggplant pieces can be larger so that they don't shrink too much when being steamed
Secondly, steaming the veggies in water can keep most of the nutritient
Thirdly, you need to remove the water before pouring the sauce, or the flavor will be diluted
Above are all the techniques for the Eggplant and Potato Cold Dish